Here's my top five strength exercises to sprint faster.
We're going to go from acceleration all the way to translating over to max velocity.
So number one kicking off is going to be the reverse lunge and all the various progressions
through an off season that come with it.
Number two is going to be a sled march, we're really focused on being able to focus on that
trajectory and then pushing through the entire motion directly correlating to acceleration.
Number three is going to be the B stance or stagger stance RDL.
Really aggressive hinge here, we're really focused on range of motion being able to put
a good stretch on those hamstrings and glutes.
Number four is going to be the step up whether you're going to go through the dumbbell all
the way progressing to the barbell more into dynamic for speed.
Step up is excellent for being able to overall increase your top speed.
Then number five is going to be working through that recovery phase after takeoff focused
on developing hamstring strength which is going to be the Nordic hamstring curl.
Make sure you have all five of those inside your programming if you're trying to sprint
faster.
Here's my top five strength exercises.